Olja Popova

Frankfurt, Hesse, Germany



oljapopova@mailbox.org



+4915170040229



linkedin.com/in/olja

Summary

Olja holds a total experience of 7 years in different industries: airline, bank, telecommunications and transport. She is experienced analysing processes and implementing improvements, structuring, preparing, conducting workshops and trainings. Her core skill is to understand both the business and technical side of a process and offer good solutions. She worked both on the business side and holds diverse hands-on technology experiences.

Experience

Product Engineer

ioki

Nov 2021 - Jun 2022 (8 months)

ioki GmbH, Frankfurt am Main; , backend team

- · prepared, conducted software trainings for new customers
- · conducted product support inhouse, trained internal stakeholders
- third level support, analysed and validated of bugs and support requests
- structured a learning platform (for the ioki products), created content
- created and maintained product documentation

Management Consultant

Accenture

Sep 2020 - Mar 2021 (7 months)

GmbH, Kronberg im Taunus; for Communications, Media & Technology for large IT transformation project

- definition and establishment of work processes (i.e. for fit-gap analysis), roles, and touchpoints in a scaled agile project (SAFe)
- · preparation, conduction, and documentation of workshops
- · consulting of Scrum teams on work processes
- · communication of iteration results
- · Confluence & Jira care

IT Auditor and Consultant

KPMG Deutschland

Jan 2015 - May 2020 (5 years 5 months)

AWS development initiative

- concept & development of an online portal (React)
- · creation and documentation of an IT-architecture based on AWS

IT-Transformation projects

· Project management (PMO), project controlling, project audit

- steering of in-between-projects communication
- creation of decision proposals regarding IT-architecture for decision making committees
- introduction of a Scrum and SAFe frameworks in a large bank Annual and other IT-Audits, IT-Audit-related work
- process design in conformity with regulatory requirements
- year-end IT audits and assessments based on other standards (ISAE3402, ISAE 3000)
- analysis of IT processes and redesign of internal control systems (IKS)

Master thesis

Scape Consulting GmbH

Oct 2013 - Jun 2014 (9 months)

Master thesis "Development of a benchmarking concept for Enterprise Architecture Management (EAM)"

Working Student

LSG Sky Chefs

Dec 2011 - Dec 2012 (1 year 1 month)

LSG Lufthansa Service Europa/Afrika GmbH - Working student

roll-out support of a production planning and steering system

Undergraduate Research Fellow

LSG Sky Chefs

Sep 2010 - Jan 2011 (5 months)

Bachelor thesis "Assessment and choice of an analytics and reporting system for SAP BW"

Education

Technische Universität Darmstadt

M.Sc. Business Informatics

R Higher School of Economics

B.Sc, Business Informatics

Skills

concept development • consulting • decision making • documentation • Product Management • Russian • English • German • Business Development • Scrum